<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


<string name="injuredtitel"> More than 33,000 injured during Quota protest in Bangladesh! </string>
    <string name="injuredtext">Since July, I have been glued to social media and international news reports on the student protests, massacre of students and subsequently, the student-led mass uprising that overthrew Bangladeshi autocrat Sheikh Hasina on Aug. 5. \n\nI am a Bangladeshi who grew up in faculty housing at Dhaka University, the epicenter of the student protests. As a child, and later as an adult, I was surrounded by Bangladeshi students and witnessed their activism and political consciousness. \n\nToday, I am incredibly moved and proud of the current generation of students who have toppled a corrupt government and are working quickly to create a working democracy in its place. This has been dubbed the “Gen Z revolution.”  \n\nAfter more than 15 years of dictatorship by Sheikh Hasina and her party, Awami League, many found it surprising to witness a student movement spark a revolution without civil war. The students endured weeks of brutal attacks by Hasina’s police force and violent Awami League members. The student protestors were demanding reforms to job quotas that crippled the country with its high youth unemployment. \n\nIn response, highly militarized police and regime loyalists killed over 500 people and injured over 1,000 in three weeks in what is called Bloody July. Today, there are more than 800 confirmed dead and more than 33,000 injured. A country-wide curfew was imposed, internet blackouts rolled out and more disappearances and massacres occurred in the dark. Democracy always dies in the dark. \n\nThe swift organizing by secular Gen Z is perhaps what surprised many. Their focus on anti-discrimination, fairness, dignity and justice swiftly expanded as teachers, parents, artists, celebrities, and average people joined the cause.\nThrough Bloody July, as more students were killed, student leaders called for a Long March to Dhaka, with one demand of Hasina’s resignation. Tens of thousands from across the country marched to the capital overnight on Aug. 5. This proverbial storming of the gates resulted in Hasina fleeing to India, her closest ally. \n\nEuphoria broke out across Bangladesh after she absconded, as people hailed this as the nation’s second independence and a return to democracy. \nThere is usually chaos in the power vacuum left after a regime falls. The police force fled their posts for fear of reprisals due to their brutal treatment of student protesters. A country suddenly without a government or a security force faced widespread looting and violence on the night of Aug. 5, mostly against Awami League members.  \n\nThe democratic movement by students responded immediately and swiftly to restore law and order that very night with the assistance of larger community support. It was nothing short of remarkable. \n\nStudents and civilians self-organized into groups to manage traffic, clean waste, guard minority religious institutions, catch culprits and vandals, remove and repair damage and rebuild infrastructure and the country at large. \nWithin a short three days of the regime’s fall, at the request of student leaders, Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus was inaugurated to lead the new interim government. It is poetic justice that Yunus replaced Hasina, who for over a decade persecuted him and filed spurious cases against him. Now, the government cabinet is the most progressive and diverse in Bangladesh’s history. \n\nThe installation of Yunus as interim head is what Bangladesh needs at this time. His first speech called to ensure the protection of all religious and ethnic minorities, prevent violence and strengthen  democratic processes to keep rebuilding Bangladesh. Calls to investigate and prosecute culprits properly, without mob justice, have been reiterated repeatedly. \n\nMonumental challenges are ahead for the desired gains of the Gen Z revolution to come to fruition. Awami League hollowed out institutions with corruption, cronyism, offshore embezzlement of funds, disappearances and extra-judicial killings, and a deeply angry set of loyalists in the country who have been cut off from sources of extortion income. \n\nThese party loyalists, alongside Hasina’s family and advisors abroad, are supporting a propaganda campaign against Bangladesh, with Hindutva support in India. Their goal is to return to power. \n\nOn Aug. 10, a mere two days after the interim government was sworn in, a judicial coup was attempted. While Yunus was paying respect to the late student protestor Abu Sayeed, the Awami League loyalist chief justice of Bangladesh attempted to declare the interim government illegal. \n\nLuckily, junior army officers alerted students, who immediately descended on the court, pressuring the chief justice to resign. Again, the vigilance, response and self-organization of students and the youth became visible.\nThere are still considerable concerns about what will transpire in the coming days and weeks as the interim government tries to bring order into the mess Hasina left behind. \n\nBut while the interim government and the people of Bangladesh work to rebuild the country, many celebrate having freedom of speech back and begin the process of healing. Now schoolchildren, parents, artists and professionals are painting murals across Bangladesh to commemorate the events and pay homage to those who paid a price to bring about change. \n\nNonetheless, there are ongoing attempts to discredit and undermine the secular students and civilians from diverse backgrounds and classes who led the uprising against a dictator who ruled with an iron fist.  \n\nAs a nation, we must rebuild and renew Bangladesh as a robust democracy. This means leaving the old dynastic party politics, guarding the democratic process, ensuring reparative justice and remaining progressive and inclusive in governance. \n\nBangladeshis have the opportunity to reform our nation. We must not go back. Bangladesh 2.0 has just started. \n\nBangladesh’s second independence builds on the long history of the anti-colonial revolutionary politics of the youth who were central in past democratic uprisings. While this one is hailed as the Gen Z revolution, these students and youth stand on the shoulders of our fierce ancestors of the past. We are better off for it. \n\n\n
</string>
    <string name="injuredsource">By Farhana Sultana - The Hill -  22 Aug 2024</string>

    ////================================================================

    <string name="arresttitel"> Arrests cross 11,000 across the country </string>
    <string name="arresttext">The total number of arrests during the ongoing raids of the law enforcement agencies has crossed 11,000 across the country till yesterday, Friday. Of them, 150 people have been arrested in 27 districts in the last 24 hours starting from Thursday afternoon to Friday afternoon.\n\nProthom Alo correspondents have been collecting information of cases filed and arrests made from sources of the city, district and thana police across the country since 17 July.\n\nAs of yesterday, information has been found of 11,112 people being arrested in connection to the clashes and violence centering the quota reform movement. So far 721 cases have been filed in total. Of them, six new cases have been filed in the last 24 hours.\n\nAccording to Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) sources, 32 persons have been arrested in the capital between Thursday 12:00 pm and Friday 12:00 pm.\n\nWith this the number of total arrests made in the capital rose to 3,039. There have been three new cases filed in Dhaka city in the last 24 hours. With this, a total of 275 cases has been found so far.\n\nApart from this, 26 cases have been registered with Dhamrai, Savar, Ashulia, Keraniganj, Nawabgabj and Dohar police stations of Dhaka district till yesterday. As many as 287 people have been arrested under these police stations.\n\nIn the last 24 hours, police has arrested 30 people in Gazipur and one in Narayanganj district. So far, a total of 536 people have been arrested in Gazipur and 608 people in Nrayanganj. Apart from that, a new case has also been filed in Nrayanganj in the last 24 hours.\n\nThree more people have been arrested in Chattogram city on Thursday night. However, there have been no new arrests in the district. With this, the total number of arrest in the city and the district rose to 992. There are total 28,200 accused in total 34 cases filed in Chattogram city and district.\n\nApart from Dhaka and Chattogram, there are comparatively more arrests in Rajshahi, Rangpur and Bogura.  There have been total 18 cases filed in Rajshahi city and district. Six people have been arrested there in the last 24 hours.\n\nMeanwhile, there have been two new cases and eight new arrests in Bogura during the last 24 hours. With this the total number of arrest there rose to 177 under a total of 17 cases.\n\nIn Khulna, two people have been arrested in the last 24 hours. With this, a total of 121 people have been arrested there. Meanwhile, eight people have been arrested afresh in Satkhira in last 24 hours.\n\nIncluding this, 137 people have been arrested there. Besides, there have been 12 fresh arrests in Jashore. And after six new arrests in Habiganj, the number of total arrests there stands at 63. \n\nThe quota reform movement started from 1 July. It spread throughout the country following a clash centering this movement of the students at the Dhaka University campus on 15 July.\n\nFrom the next day, there were incidents of demonstrations, clashes, vandalism, arson and deaths centering the movement in different parts of the country. The law enforcement agencies have been carrying out arrest drives since then.\n\nReportedly, a large number of the people arrested across the country are leaders and activists of BNP, Jamaat-e-Islami and affiliated organisations of the two parties. \n\nPlus, leaders and activists of various parties and organisations who participate in movements with BNP are also being arrested. Students are being arrested as well. The police however claim that only the people involved in attacks and violence are being arrested. \n\n\n

</string>
    <string name="arrestsource">Prothom Alo -  03 Aug 2024</string>



</resources>